lantic.net 2018-05-06

# Privacy Policy | Vox Telecom | A Leading South African Telecoms Operator

VOX PRIVACY POLICY

The purpose of Vox Telecom’s privacy policy is to assure customers that we respect their privacy rights, by undertaking to not trade in their personal details or monitor their communications except when required to do so by law.

The policy also tells our customers how and when we will gather their personal information as well as how we intend to use it. Furthermore, the policy gives our customers an avenue of redress if our company or any of its employees do so.

1\. WHAT IS OUR POLICY ON CUSTOMER INFORMATION?

From time to time, Vox Telecom will collect certain personal information about our customers and visitors from their websites, when we host these. Such information will include both identifiable personal data, as well as non-identifiable personal information. Identifiable personal information will be collected when you sign a contract for service with us.

Non-identifiable information is gathered automatically when you visit our website or those websites hosted by us and stored for use in our system. The purpose of this privacy policy is to explain to customers what types of information we will collect and how that information is used. In most cases, we collect this information to ensure network integrity and that we continue to provide you with the most relevant content and best possible service that suits your needs. In some cases, we are required by law to collect personal information about customers. Except where the law requires otherwise, we undertake to protect the confidentiality of such data.

2\. CONFIDENTIALITY

Vox Telecom respects the privacy of our customers and the privacy of those accessing our network and websites hosted by us. We undertake to protect the confidentiality of our customers and users including all personal information supplied in the course of contracting with us for services. We undertake not to sell your personal information to third parties for commercial or marketing purposes.  
3\. COLLECTION OF PERSONAL DATA

Vox Telecom collects personal data about our customers when they apply for a new service subscription, respond to customer surveys and promotions or contact our helpdesk.

4\. USE OF PERSONAL DATA

Vox Telecom may on occasion use your personal information to contact you about promotional offers; advise you of matters relevant to service provision and in some cases, solicit your feedback. However, Vox Telecom will provide you with an option within every communication to opt out of receiving any communications of this nature or you can contact our customer services representatives to ensure that you do not receive such promotional information, at unsubscribe@voxtelecom.co.za. We may also log the websites you visit; collect IP addresses and information about your operating system and the type of browser you use for the purposes of our network/ system administration and to audit the use of our site. This data, however, will not be used to identify individual users who will at all times remain anonymous. Any information Vox Telecom collects from you through correspondence with us, whether via e-mail, telephonically or by written letter, will only be used to address the matters within that correspondence. If this requires referring such correspondence within Vox Telecom or to a third party to ensure customer service, your personal information will only be disclosed to the point necessary to address your query or concerns, and will otherwise be kept confidential.

5\. PUBLIC SPACE (BULLETIN BOARDS, CHAT ROOMS AND THIRD-PARTY SITES)

Any information that customers disclose in a public space, including on any bulletin board, chat room or any site Vox Telecom may host for you, is available to anyone else who visits that space.  
Vox Telecom cannot safeguard any information you disclose there.

6\. SITE LINKING

Sites hosted Vox Telecom may contain links to sites that belong to third parties unrelated to us. Vox Telecom cannot be held responsible for any use of your personal information arising from you disclosing such information on third party sites. Vox Telecom cannot protect any information you may disclose on these sites and recommends that you review the privacy policy statements of those sites you visit. Vox Telecom reserves the right to disclose information about customers where required in good faith, to do so by law or to exercise our legal rights or defend ourselves against legal claims.

7\. TYPES OF INFORMATION

There are two main types of personal information – Identifiable personal data, and non-identifiable personal data. Identifiable data generally includes a customer’s name, address, telephone numbers, gender, IP address, billing information (such as a credit card number) etc. Non-identifiable data generally includes: a postal code; the date and time sites are accessed (if you gather this); pages visited; (usually done to monitor demand and improve usefulness of the site); the type of browser being used; the operating system and the type of personal computer being used to access the services. In terms of the Regulation of Interception of Communications and Provision of Communications-Related Information Act, 2002, all telecoms service providers, including ISPs are obliged to obtain and keep certain identifiable personal data of customers when entering into service contracts. This includes in addition to the above, in the case of a person: ID number; residential and business addresses; and a certified copy of the customer’s ID document. In the case of a company: all of the above as well as the company’s registration number and a certified copy of the customer’s business letterhead. While this expansive interpretation of personal information might be seen as overly cautious, we advise you to identify or define all these requirements as personal information.

8\. REMARKETING

Vox uses 3rd party vendor re-marketing tracking cookies, including the Google Adwords tracking cookie. This means we will continue to show ads to you across the internet, specifically on the Google Content Network (GCN). As always we respect your privacy and are not collecting any identifiable information through the use of Google’s or any other 3rd party remarketing system.

The third-party vendors, including Google, whose services we use – will place cookies on web browsers in order to serve ads based on past visits to our website. – Third-party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on a user’s prior visits to your website. This allows us to make special offers and continue to market our services to those who have shown interest in our service.
